Guide to the Pamela B. Gann Papers, 1990-2007, undated UA.20.02.0002
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Pamela B. Gann Papers
1989-2007, undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Gann, Pamela B., 1948-
UA.20.02.0002
15.5 Linear Feet
Pamela Gann served as the Dean of the Duke University Law School from 1988 to 1999. The Pamela B. Gann Papers include materials from Pamela Gann's time as Dean of the Duke University Law School.
Biographical / Historical
Pamela Gann served as the Dean of the Duke University Law School from 1988 to 1999.
Pamela Gann was born in North Carolina and attended the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, graduating in 1970 with a degree in mathematics. She attended Duke University Law School and graduated in 1973, then practiced law for two years before returning to Duke as a professor of tax and international law. She became Dean of Duke Law in 1988 and served in that role until 1999. During her time as Dean, she established a summer international program in Europe and Asia, expanded the public law program, prioritized environmental studies and made interdisciplinary connections with the Nicholas School of the Environment, and led the Law School's first capital campaign, raising more than $17 million.
In 1999 Gann left Duke Law to become the president of Claremont McKenna College in California. She is a fellow of the American Bar Foundation, and served on the Board of Directors of the Council on Foreign Relations, the International Women's Forum, and the American Law Institute. An endowed professorship at Duke Law, the Pamela B. Gann Professor of Law, is named for her.
Access Restrictions
For a period of twenty-five years from the origin of the material, permission in writing from the office of origin and the University Archivist is required for use. After twenty-five years, records that have been processed may be consulted with the permission of the University Archivist.
Provenance
The Pamela B. Gann Papers were received by the Duke University Archives as a transfer in 2017.
Related Materials
Paul D. Carrington Papers, Duke University Archives, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University.
School of Law Records, Duke University Archives, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University.
School of Law Reference Collection, Duke University Archives, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University.
Collection Overview
The Pamela B. Gann Papers include materials from Pamela Gann's time as Dean of the Duke University Law School. Included are files related to international travel, administration and operations of the Law School, the 1990s addition to the Law School building, correspondence, and other materials. Materials have not been screened or processed beyond a folder-level inventory.
Conditions Governing Access
Records, such as search committee files or others pertaining to employment where individuals are identified, are closed for 70 years.
Conditions Governing Access
Records of the University's Board of Trustees which have been in existence for at least fifty years are available for scholarly research with the permission of the University Archivist. Access to records which have been in existence for less than fifty years shall be granted only by special permission, in writing, from the Board of Trustees.
Duke University. School of Law
- Subject Files, 1
  - Administration (University) (Box 1)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Restricted until 2024
  - Admissions #1 (Box 1)
  - Admissions #2 (Box 1)
  - AIDS Clinic/Course #1 (Box 1)
  - AIDS Clinic/Course #2 (Box 1)
  - American Law Institute (Box 1)
  - American Academy of Arts & Science (Box 1)
  - Arts & Censorship Display 1998 (Box 1)
    Restricted until 2023
  - Asian International University - Thailand (Box 1)
  - Board of Trustees Meeting, December 3-4, 1999, Dean Havighurst (Box 1)
    Restricted until 2049
  - Board of Trustees Meeting, October 1-2, 1999, Dean Havighurst (Box 1)
  - Board of Trustees Misc. (Box 1)
  - Brussels Summer Program (Box 1)
  - Burness, John (Box 1)
  - Global Capital Markets Center #1 (Box 1)
  - Global Capital Markets Center #2 (Box 1)
  - Center on Comparative Studies (Box 1)
  - Center for Creative Leadership (Box 1)
  - Center w/ Environmental School #1 (Box 1)
  - Center w/ Environmental School #2 (Box 1)
  - Center on Health Law (Box 1)
  - Center on Intellectual Property (Box 1)
  - Center for Racial Justice (Box 1)
  - Center for Study of Congress (Box 1)
  - Clinical Education (Box 2)
  - Clinics (Box 2)
  - Comparative Law School Data (Box 2)
  - Computing (Box 2)
  - Computing #2 (Box 2)
  - Computing #3 (Box 2)
  - Curriculum Committee (Box 2)
  - Council on Foreign Affairs (Box 2)
  - Curriculum Review (Box 2)
  - Duke in Denmark (Box 2)
  - DUMAC (Box 2)
  - Duke Press (Box 2)
  - Economists (Box 2)
  - Entreprenuerial Advisory Task Force (Box 2)
  - Environmental Law Society (Box 2)
  - Externship (International Law) (Box 2)
  - Financial Aid (Box 2)
  - Ford Foundation (Box 2)
  - Fuqua (Box 2)
  - Gay & Lesbian Issues (Box 2)
  - Geneva (Box 2)
  - Minor Faculty Recruitment (Box 2)
  - Haagen (Box 2)
  - Hong Kong - Inaugural Institute 1995 (Box 2)
    Restricted until 2020
  - International Studies (Box 2)
  - International Law Society (Box 2)
  - HIID's International Public Finance Group (Box 3)
  - Internationalization (Box 3)
  - International Affairs Committee (Box 3)
  - International Law Organization (Box 3)
  - JD/LLM #1 (Box 3)
  - JD/LLM #2 (Box 3)
  - JD/MA (Box 3)
  - JD/PhD English (Box 3)
  - JD/PhD (Poli Sci) (Box 3)
  - Journals Committee (Box 3)
  - Journals (Box 3)
  - Journals - International & Comparative (Box 3)
  - Journals - DLJ (Box 3)
  - Gender Journal Conference on Higher Education (Box 3)
  - Journals - Gender (Box 3)
  - L&CP Conference on Soviet Union (Box 3)
  - Journals - L&CP (Box 3)
  - Judicial Clerkships (Box 3)
  - Keck Conference 1995 (Box 3)
  - Keohane (Box 3)
  - Legal Research & Writing (Box 3)
  - Library #2 (Box 3)
  - Library (Box 3)
  - Long Range Plng. (Box 3)
  - Mandatory Retirement (Box 3)
  - Masters of Engineering Mgmt. (Box 3)
  - Loan Forgiveness (Box 4)
  - Loan Forgiveness (Box 4)
  - Minority Affairs (Box 4)
  - Minority Financial Aid by Firms (Box 4)
  - Minority Recruitment (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous #1 (Box 4)
  - MLS (Box 4)
  - Moot Court (Box 4)
  - MPC (Curzan) - Graduate Student Housing (Box 4)
  - Mosteller (Box 4)
  - NC Bar (Box 4)
  - NC Bar - Bench & Bar Liaison (Box 4)
  - New Grading System (Box 4)
  - Nomenclature (Box 4)
  - Private Adjudication Center #1 (Box 4)
  - Private Adjudication Center #2 (Box 4)
  - Private Adjudication Center #3 (Box 4)
  - Sexual Harassment/Discrimination #1 (Box 4)
  - Sexual Harassment/Discrimination #2 (Box 4)
  - Sexual Harassment/Discrimination #3 (Box 4)
  - Sexual Harassment/Discrimination #4 (Box 5)
  - Student Funded Fellowships (Box 5)
  - Student Housing Working Group 1990 (Box 5)
- Correspondence, 2
  - Deans Council (Box 5)
  - Deans Council (Box 5)
  - Provost (Box 5)
  - (Women?) (Box 5)
  - University Professors (Box 5)
  - untitled folder (Box 5)
  - Title IX (Box 5)
  - untitled folder (Box 5)
  - Board, Visitors (Box 5)
  - untitled folder (Box 5)
  - Provost (Carrington) (Box 5)
  - untitled folder (Box 5)
  - Deans Council (Box 5)
  - Board of Visitors (Box 5)
  - untitled folder (Box 6)
  - Women's Professional Forum (Box 6)
  - Women Executives (Box 6)
  - Women Law Deans (Box 6)
  - International Women's Forum (IWF) (Box 6)
  - ACE (Box 6)
  - untitled folder (Box 6)
  - Canadian Conference (Box 6)
  - Council on Foreign Relations (Box 6)
  - Duke Bar Association (Box 6)
  - untitled folder (Box 6)
- International Travel, 3
  - Japan (Box 6)
  - Korea (Box 6)
  - Taiwan (Box 6)
  - External Relations Projects (Box 6)
  - Germany (Box 6)
  - German Consulate (Box 7)
  - China 1995 (Box 7)
  - Hong Kong (Box 7)
  - International Correspondence (Box 7)
  - Manila/Hanoi Trip 1995 (Box 7)
  - Philippines (Box 7)
  - Hong Kong, 1994 (Box 7)
  - Japan Fundraising (Box 7)
  - Asia Trip, 1993 (Box 7)
  - Asia Trip, 1993 (Box 7)
  - Vietnam Program on International Trade (Box 7)
  - Vietnam (Box 7)
  - South Africa/Europe 1996 (Box 7)
    Restricted until 2021
  - China/Hong Kong (Box 7)
  - Bill Arthur (China) (Box 7)
  - China Agreement (Box 7)
  - Hong Kong/Taiwan/Vietnam (Box 7)
  - untitled folder (Box 7)
  - Japan Travel 1991 (Box 7)
  - Panama Trip 1998 (Box 7)
  - European Trip 1995 (Box 7)
  - Europe Trip 1995 (Box 7)
  - Jackson Hole VIII May 2005 (Box 7)
    Restricted until 2030
  - Jackson Hole May 2003 (Box 7)
    Restricted until 2028
  - Jackson Hole [?] 2005 (Box 8)
  - Conference Call re 2007 Development Conference (Box 8)
- Other Files, 4
  - Forms (Box 8)
  - Faculty (Box 8)
  - untitled folder (Box 8)
  - untitled folder (Box 8)
  - Mosteller (Box 8)
  - Beale (Box 8)
  - Ep (Box 8)
  - BOV Administration (Box 8)
  - New BOV's (Box 8)
  - Resumes of 3 Finalists for Associate Dean A&D 1/08 (Box 8)
    Restricted until 2069
  - BOV (Box 8)
  - untitled folder (Box 8)
  - Fax Forms (Box 8)
  - Time Log (Box 8)
  - untitled folder (Box 8)
  - untitled folder (Box 8)
  - Associate Dean for Alumni & Development (Box 8)
  - Board of Visitors #2 (Box 8)
  - Board of Visitors (Box 8)
  - Class Schedules (Box 8)
  - Faculty #2 (Box 8)
  - Review of the "Whole Person" Committee Recommendations for the Capital Campaign, 1997 (Box 9)
    Restricted until 2022.
- Building Files, 1989-1997
  - Building (1-2 of 4), 1989-1990; 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Building (3-4 of 4), 1990-1995; 2 folders (Box 9)
    Restricted until 2020.
  - Phase 3, 1994-1995 (Box 9)